Okay,
yeah, Paula, you can
have the first saying.
Yeah, hi, everybody.
Welcome to the second office
hour of this semester.
And as usual, we are going to
respond to the
question you posted,
Inad. So I'll let
the word to Shin
to guide us through
the process.
Okay, yeah. So hello, everyone.
And yeah, this is the second
office hour. I hope all
students are safe. I
understand that we have the
winter storm breaking the
East Park Cup of the U.S.
But anyway, so we have
assignment two due earlier
today in the morning and
A3 already open. and this
Saturday we will have we
will have assignment 4
open and this week student
should be so during
this week let me see so
student should be watching
the requirement engineering
and the two external
sources JUnit and
IntelliJ Okay, besides the
assignment three, we also
have the participation quiz
opening. So don't forget
about that because it's
supposed to be easy, simple
giveaway points only.
All right. So, and one
more thing, I also posted
the grade statistics and
grading updates on it.
As mentioned before
and emphasized again,
you will see that
assignment six is somewhat
having a bigger spread
than the remaining.
So have your expectation
management in check.
All right.
Other than that, I think
we can have the first
question, which I'm happy
to let Paula answer that.
What makes a good test?
Paula, you are muted.
I know. I'm muted. class
with me and so honestly one
you know uh could could
teach a full class on that
i actually think i i did a
full half class of it right
uh and so uh so you know
let's but let's keep it
short uh on this so like
uh so first of all a test
should measure what is supposed
to measure right so has
to be a valid test and uh
and second uh it has to
be reliable so it has to
give you consistent result
um and um you know and uh
so somehow so these are the
two main things right so
if we um what else uh you
need to choose the tasks
that make it uh make it
discriminate in in a meaningful
way uh so you want to
separate what what uh if
you write a good test we can
we can we can see and like
you you can when we look
on our side we can see the
people that really understood
the people that partially
understood and that that
who don't yet right if
you think about that so
somehow uh bad test cluster
every uh everyone at the top
or at the bottom right if
you think about that and
then last things um you
need to write so you cannot
you cannot test everything
so you need uh to uh matches
the uh a good test needs
to matches the level of
thinking you care about um
and so um what else says
maybe another important
thing is say that it's uh uh
it's fair and accessible so
fair but fair doesn't mean
easy right uh it means
not biased uh and then of
course okay now maybe i
should have said this at the
very beginning a test need
to to provide you uh useful
feedback if you if you don't
understand the feedback
from your test so but this
is becoming a little bit
a little bit more in
yeah it goes a little bit
more in depth I think I stand
probably actually I was
thinking I'm going I should
have got prepared because
it was in an ad but I read
it three seconds before we
came in I think I stand by
Validity and reliability.
So consistent
result and aligns in
measure what it's
supposed to measure.
Yes. So on top of what
Paula said, I think because
we are cut up just three
weeks into the semester
only, later on you will
learn more about tests. we
have blackboard testing,
whiteboard testing, etc.
And then you will also learn
the concept of test plan,
test suite, and test
cases. Because when you ask
what makes a good test,
it's hard for the people to
answer, right? And then
probably have to like give
a lot of context just to
go into their validity.
So I wanted to be very vague
at this point because you
haven't studied also all
the kind of way in which you
can write your tests and so
I was trying to stay on a
general bit on a general
and I think you know and I
feel if I want to stay on
the philosophical case if you
think about tests in software
engineering and the word
test is used also in the
real world is the same exact
things right so what makes
a good test in real life
like as a professor if i if
you write a test for your
student uh what are you doing
you're trying to measure
that you're trying to make
sure a good test i would
love for my student to say
a good test is a test that
that measure what i wanted
you know what i try to teach
you right and so a good
test in software engineering
is a test that try to to to
to check the things you care
about now you can do it
what do you care about then
you learn you might care
about covering some part of
your code or you might care
about checking some property
without looking at the code
it depends it's it's an
equivalence right it's it's
really i don't think that
in software so in software
engineering a lot of words
exist also in the real world
right already we didn't
invent them we just use them
in this context and I think
it's because it's the same
idea as just in a different
context so but when you
don't have the tools yet I
try to stay on a philosophical
level because sorely as
Shin was saying you don't
really know it's enough to to
answer to this question but
maybe when we go back when
we go further in the semester
and you are at different
stages we can you know we
can look into that more.
Thanks Paula. So
the next question,
when can we know our
group assignments?
This is the logistic
of the course. So I
think we did mention
that last of this hour,
the students will
know that during
assignment five and GPD zero,
the one or two days
before gpd0 opens
and deliverable 0 is
just a simple contact
information so don't
stress about that
the reason we wait until
that late to form the group
is because we it's because
sometimes students are
dropped across and we don't
want to form the groups
and then some students drop
and And then it becomes
in the group has two few
members that it is becoming
unviable groups. So that's
why we wait until one
or two days before D0 opens
and have the assignment.
okay so it seems we
only have two questions
so far both of which
already answered
um meanwhile any anything
new from uh from you paula
something from the academia
oh yeah now you know like
what I want to grasp your
okay assuming I have to
give a talk and I have two
different topics to pick
from I'll tell you the
topics they are both software
engineering related both
requirements so that I don't
know if you read my bio but
one of the two things I do
most is requirements
engineering that is you know
the beginning of a project
when you collect requirements
for building your your
solution okay I need to give
a talk that talks about
things I already done and
things that I will do and my
two options so okay no and
my story is the following
okay it's what do I care
about when I do research
is I think humans will be
always necessary in certain
activity and so my goal is
always to try to create
support for humans to be better
in doing those activities
right and so I work a
lot on requirements and
dissertation interviews and now
I'm working a lot also on
try to help for certain
type kind of software
development and I know you know
already this but I'm saying
it also for the students
you need to use formal
specification because it's
required because of the
kind of software that is
critical and you know if it
fails people might die it's
just a lot of money get
lost right And so I've done
already a lot of work
before, and now I'm trying
to understand how LLMs can
support these activities.
And so in one direction, we
are using LLMs to analyze
the preparation of a
person before going to a
requirement solicitation
interview. The other work is to
try to not to translate
natural language informal
requirements that are very
difficult, because I think
it's very risky because
at some point you get
confident in the result of a
tool that is never perfect.
And so the purpose is to
try to explain formulas
that you write in natural
language so that you can have
feedback on the correctness
of your sentence and
reason about that, like
human in the loop. Now it's
much more complicated, but
these are the two topics.
Formal requirements,
support for formal
requirements or support
for interviews.
What would you pick?
I'm collecting votes.
I am looking... Well,
I think it's because
we are interacting
with students on
ad, so maybe we
have to wait a
little bit for that.
So students, please just
comment on the ad thread,
so which topic... You
can also have a vote.
Yeah. Well, I mean, if I
choose to have the vote,
then the LLM formal verification
sounds really interesting
to me because I have
been involved with both.
and the fact that because I
also do vibe coding myself
and the thing is the LM
just keep forgetting or keep
doing the wrong thing that
I explicitly tell them
to do like recently I
explicitly tell them to do TDD
and then actually they
have the plan like when in
order like step one do
something step two do something
step three uh run the test
uh set four do something
but they just keep writing
the code and they they
never run the test so they
go one two three four six
seven and then step five
never get completed so it's
uh again hallucination so
i'm really interested how
can we uh because for me,
yes, formal verification,
it's like a lawyer,
so the lawyer language
is everything is like
exact meaning that
can be never like
double meaning, right?
I'm translating natural
language, informal language,
automatically, without
mistake, it's impossible
because natural language
is intrinsically ambiguous
so this is why the human
is needed but i want to say
i was building a gold
standard and i may mistake
myself because um after
you are in this formula for
a very very long time it's
easy to make a mistake
yeah so yeah that's why i
mean if it is my choice and
i would really interested
in that i just don't know
how but on the other hand
you are a professor so
you have a like new research,
like novel research.
Yeah, I have both,
I mean, both things
I have, I have, I've
been working on,
on formal verification
since my PhD.
So I don't want to say
how many years, but
wait, and, and then in
requirements for more
than 10 years at this
point. So in there,
and yeah, we got a
question. So we were so
entertaining that we got
a new question. Yeah,
so what can we do to prepare
for future assignments?
If we get a good score
in Grayscope, does it
mean we did not use any
non-allow libraries or
just making sure I'm
not? Okay, yeah, so what
can we do to prepare
for future assignments?
Well, I mean,
watch the lecture,
read the assignment
instruction clearly, follow
the assignment
instruction clearly, and
follow the feedback
from Grayscope. So every
semester we have students
like violate any combination
of those three, did
not watch the lecture,
did not follow the
assignment instruction,
nor did or did not
resolve Gradescope
feedback, especially
with certain manual
graded, manually
graded assignment.
we still have sanity check
and if Grayscope say you
have to do something
otherwise you will get zero it
does mean you will get a
zero regardless of what it
could have been when it is
manually graded so that's one
thing and it is connected
to the second part um if
you if students get good
score on Grayscope. In other
words, if Grayscope is happy,
then yes, mostly we are
fine. We only run final
human manual check on
plagiarism. And if you, one,
did not plagiarize, two, did
not use AI-assisted coding,
then you should be fine.
Again, do not violate
code of conduct. And then
the rest. If Grayscope
happy, then you're good.
So that's the logistic.
Paula, do you have any
comment on that?
On the logistic? No, because
I'm getting used to it
myself, but I'm preparing
for the next assignment. I
second everything that Shin
say and try to make sure,
you know, like you, when
you read the assignment that
you can make this step from
I listen to like in some
of the in some of the part
and some of the lecture
you also see more practical
stuff but some you know
you need to learn the
foundation so try to make sure
you can do this step to move
forward so it depends on
the assignment but my
suggestion is always this and it
applies in software
development less than in for
instance I took many years
theoretical computer science
but very often there is
much more time in thinking
and planning than in actually
doing right so make sure
that when you read the
assignment you take that time
to think you know and build
your plan for solving it
it's because if you're
rushing the solution then
then if at some point
you realize that that was
wrong it's so much so
much undoing right so make
sure you arrive at the
end you make your plan
and you go to the solution
but it's much more
thinking than doing that's
or planning than doing
okay cool so next question
um if someone took the
course in prior semester are
they allowed to reuse some
code from their personal
assignments uh for this we
explicitly have it in the
syllabus so please make sure
that you already read the
syllabus and if you already
did and still have the same
question please come back
to us because it means
that we did not do our job
good enough explaining in
the syllabus that you have to
ask the question even after
that and also you have to
read the syllabus anyway because
we have the participation
and syllabus quiz coming
due and And if you
don't read the syllabus and
answer incorrectly, then you
would be sad because it's
essentially three points.
Next question, does the
skeleton code generated
by IntelliJ count as
AI-generated code?
So the skeleton
or the boilerplate
generated by IntelliJ
is not considered AI
-generated. it. So
yeah, that is fine.
Meaning that like five
years ago before LOM, right,
we already have the
boilerplate code.
So yeah, the team only
look at the project
specific code that
the students do.
Okay, no more questions.
So, Paula, maybe we
can spend time a little
bit on those topics.
Which topics? My
topics or other topics?
Yeah, your topics.
Okay, so what do
you want to know?
Oh, no, we have
another question.
Students definitely say
it's interesting to me how
often yes and you know okay
so let me say something
about interview before llms
so i started to study
interviews maybe in 2014 for 13
2013 no 14 2014 uh and uh And
we did an analysis because
in 2016 there was the
silver jubilee of the main
conference in requirements
engineering and we submitted
this proposal for a talk
on requirement solicitation
and we did an analysis of
all the research, corporate
research published about
requirement solicitation,
right? And so there was a
very interesting study that
shows that when you do
requirements, when you analyze
your requirement specification
it's already too late
even if you do a full
analysis the mistake you find
there are not problem of how
you wrote your requirements
or conflicts that you didn't
resolve are problem of
things that you didn't find
during your requirements
phase and our requirement
solicitation interview are the
most common way to collect
your requirements and it's
interesting because you
know like very often people
think about yes but this is
common sense it's like me
talking with my client or
talking with other stakeholders
right yes but it's not
the same thing because
there is a gap in domain
knowledge because you're not
talking to your colleague but
you're talking to a person
in a completely different
domain because there is
there is no there is no report
created already with this
person and so we did an
initial very interesting study
to try to analyze the most
common mistake that young
analysts do and so we did
it with a lot of master's
students that were already
professionals so they had
already an undergraduate
degree in computing so they
already study requirements
and most likely have talked
with somebody outside their
field and then we did all
these very long analysis
it was very time consuming
I listened to this interview
we transcribed all of them
and we identified this
most common mistake that um
that uh that younger um uh
analysts do and we use them
somehow to create a sort of
training in reverse order
so that you practice and
then use them and so now for
instance i would be very
excited it's been quite long
time that i haven't worked
on that part but i think
it would be quite exciting
uh to rebuild this training
with some support of you
know what was very expensive
for me to do I've been teaching
a class on requirements
engineering for instance
and so you had time to
work really on the different
aspect and what was anyway
too much time consuming
was like to you know train
on interviews with students
and now we you know LLMs
and this ability to you know
to create an agent that can
be the customer students
can have you know people can
can can be easily can eat
more ease I mean not super
easily but it's uh there
could be this idea of training
because I don't think
despite the fact that LLMs
can be the interviewer I think
people will have to remain
the interview that in in
the in the last year I've
seen a couple of paper on
them and I've seen them
presented and asked questions
while While technically
they are very interesting
from a practical perspective,
I don't think that
many of the problems
that were before young
junior analysts do,
they are in the
relationship in the way in
which you communicate
and you listen and react.
So I don't think that this
will ever… maybe a new
elicitation technique in between
questionnaire an interview
can be created through LLMs
but I think that interview
will stay and so if I
think that analysts need
training to go and talk with
their client and so I'm very
curious about you know how
what we studied before that
was very interesting but a
lot of time consuming for
a training part because
you need you know you need
trainee to be able to have a
fake customer to talk to and
we try to create an intelligent
agent but you know like
LLM's changed completely
shifted completely the
ability of you know communication
in in terms of natural
language processing and so
now what we tried to do before
with pre-casted things
might be much easier so I
don't know I think I
actually think this is a very
fascinating problem see I said
this is my problem Sheen that
I I am completely passionate
about everything I do.
I have a question,
though. So with the
requirement
engineering, it is semi
-structured interview.
Is that right?
So you prepare certain
questions, but then going...
So you prepare... So requirements
and decision interviews,
semi-structured as one
type. but usually and so
usually they are unstructured
the one that you have
you have you create kind of
a set of topics you want to
cover and then and so this
this is there is a preparation
semi-structure is in
between but usually at the
very beginning of the project
the interviews are fully
unstructured because you
really otherwise you know
you want to have the freedom
to really understand uh
despite the fact that uh
it's it's very interesting
we are uh very much biased
i mean tend to bias the
customer and another thing
that we we at some point we
did a study in which we
tried to follow um a process
right to see to go from id
from an idea to a you know
to a requirements what
happened in between and so we
had a sequence of interviews
and then we were seeing
that we're seeing the notes
and the requirements and
then funny enough in all
this interview there were no
mention of many non-functional
requirements like you
know privacy or security
technical things that the
customer that your client
is I don't remember what was
the topic but assuming you
know a person that has a
summer camp for children okay
because this has been very
often one of the to me. I
had little children at the
time, so it looked like a
very important problem to
me. But, you know, of
course, for some reason, we
noticed that these were
questions that were not asked and
certain requirements came
up. These were like, you
know, a request from
them. So it's really, it's
interesting. But I mean, semi
-structured interview, I used
like maybe a second, a
third interview with the
same stakeholder to
make sure you call, in
theory, if you follow
rightly the process, right?
And you have a structured
interview at the
beginning with your main
stakeholders in which
you try to understand
which are the other
stakeholders that you
didn't consider. And then
when you go back to look
at what you collected,
you have these things that
you need to understand
better. And then you can
go in a more structured way
completely passionate
so that was saying
in the meantime but
thank you for the vote
okay nice so we don't have
any other questions so
probably we can wait a little
bit more and then if not then
yeah it's still early in the
semester so it is expected
there are some some great
questions like the first
question we have but it's
also hard for us to answer
right now given that we are
just really early and we
the students may not have
enough contacts but let's take
a note for us to respond to
that later in the semester
every time they learn
something more about us Yeah.
I'm counting on your
memory, not mine,
or on the student to
repost the question.
OK, so if there are
no other questions,
then I think we can
call it a night.
And yeah, we will see all of
you on it. and
next office hour.
Yeah.
Okay.
Bye.
Bye guys.